MARK LOEGEL

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

269-271-2514

Madison Heights, MI meloegel@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/mark-loegel

https://markloegel.vercel.app/

https://github.com/meloegel

A full stack web developer that specializes in React and Node. My experience at Lambda school has given me confidence shipping modern web applications on cross-functional development teams. I have a passion for programming and enjoy the pursuit of new technologies.

TECH STACK

- · Core Skills: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Git
- <u>Front End</u>: React, Redux, Context, MaterialUI, ReactStrap, MapBox, React-Map-GL, PlotlyJs, Ant Design, SemanticUI
- <u>Back End</u>: NodeJS, Knex, Express, PostgresSQL, SQLite3, GraphQL, MySQL
- <u>Testing</u>: Cypress, Jest and Supertest and React Testing Library
- Experience with Docker, RESTful API, Unit testing, npm, yarn, SASS/LESS

SKILLS

- · Agile Project Management
- Analyze complex technical information
- Design, analyze and implement database structures
- Team leadership
- Pair-programming
- · Remote work and remote learning

EDUCATION HISTORY LAMBDA SCHOOL

Web Development & Computer Science, 2020

- Produced numerous production quality web applications
- Experience with agile software development methods
- Participated in the Lambda Leadership program
- Part of the Lambda X Endorsement program

OAKLAND UNIVERSITY

Psychology with Focus in Child Development, 2012 Member of Swimming and Diving Team, 2008–2012

- Division 1 Program
- Conference Champions all 4 years

PREVIOUS WORK EXPERIENCE

Collaborative Advantage Marketing
Building/Construction Manager | 2017–2019
Goldfish Swim School Franchising
Operations Consultant | 2015–2017
Goldfish Swim School Rochester/Macomb
Manager On Duty | 2013 –2015

A full stack web developer that specializes in React RELEVANT PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

BRIDGES TO PROSPERITY | OCT 2020 | BRIDGESTOPROSPERITY.ORG FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

NODE | EXPRESS | JEST | REACT | ANT DESIGN | MATERIAL UI | MAPBOX | PLOTLY

- Worked on a cross-functional team of 4 data scientists and 4 web developers over 4
 weeks to display data generated by the Data Science team on a map for the
 stakeholder to better be able to evaluate new and existing bridge site locations
- Added topography and different icons to the map functionality
- Integrated new output from our data scientist's model into our backend API service
- Updated the styling of the app to match the current web site
- With my personal updates of adding topography and adding graphs with PlotlyJs our version of the project was chosen to continue to build on by the stakeholder

ULTRAMIKRO | NOV 2020 | ULTRAMIKRO.VERCEL.APP

FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

REACT | MATERIAL UI

- Contracted to recover what was possible from previous site and create and deploy new site
- Originally created the project in HTML in approximately 3 days. Deployed May 2020
- Re-created the site in React in Oct in approximately 3 days. Deployed Oct 2020
- Stakeholder happy with new site, remain in contact for future updates of the site

PROJECTS

CONWAY'S GAME OF LIFE | 2020 | <u>GITHUB REPO</u> | <u>DEPLOYED LINK</u> FRONT END DEVELOPER

REACT| SASS | JEST

- · Created Conway's Game of Life(CGOL) in React in a week
- Built a version of CGOL in Python. This project was made using React and was a great opportunity for me to hone my JS skills

RUN TRACKER | 2020 | GITHUB REPO <u>FE</u> / <u>BE</u> | <u>DEPLOYED LINK</u> FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

NODE | EXPRESS | POSTGRES/SQLITE | JEST | REACT | SASS | MATERIAL UI | CYPRESS

- · Created an app that will track running times and can publish runs to a public feed
- Back End uses Jest for Testing, Front End uses Cypress
- · Back End is deployed on Heroku, Front End on Vercel

BUILD WEEK - HOW TO | 2020 | GITHUB REPO

BACK END WEB DEVELOPER

NODE | EXPRESS | POSTGRES/SQLITE | JEST

- Created the Back End for the project
- Favorite project while at Lambda, loved learning how to write an elaborate and well documented readme

BUILD WEEK - WATER MY PLANTS | 2020 | GITHUB REPO

FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

REACT | YUP | STYLED-COMPONENTS | FORMIK

- Created entirety of front end of app with exception of login and register
- · Worked closely with the Back End engineer to help plan out the database schema

BUILD WEEK - ANYWHERE FITNESS | 2020 | GITHUB REPO

FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

REACT | YUP | STYLED-COMPONENTS

- Worked on a project with many different cohorts in a group of 9
- Collaborated across different teams to complete this project, worked in a group with Data Scientist and an iOS Team to deliver the product on time.